[Coroner's Diary]
[Episode 35]
What Ms. Qin has said
matches your investigation results
completely.
Yes.
Why isn't Wan speaking?
Your Majesty,
Princess Zhaoyu is my elder sister.
I should avoid speaking on the matter.
Besides, she has caused such a disaster,
I am too ashamed to face Your Majesty.
If Your Majesty wishes to punish someone,
please punish me instead.
Why would I punish you?
You have nothing to do with this matter.
Get up, get up.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
The Prince Yan Che's escape
has nothing to do with Ms. Qin.
As for the fire incident,
I...
cannot bear to blame her any further.
However,
it would be inappropriate for Ms. Qin
to remain in the restricted quarters.
Considering she was newly married
when she became implicated
in Prince Yan Che's affairs.
Here's what we'll do.
I
graciously permit her to return
to the Marquis of Zhongyong's Mansion,
to rest and recover peacefully.
She must not leave without my decree.
And a royal physician
will attend to her daily.
Wan.
I show her such mercy
partly because you and she
come from the same family.
However, this matter
should not be publicized
to avoid
further complications.
Yes.
Thank you for Your Majesty's benevolence.
Recently,
the Empress Dowager has been unwell.
When you have time,
come to the palace more often
to keep Her Majesty company.
Yes.
You may go now.
Your Highness, please wait a moment.
I'll go inform them of your arrival.
Why were you distracted earlier?
I just find it strange
that His Majesty acts so coldly
towards Yan Che.
He is his only legitimate son.
Even if he despises his lack of ambition,
he shouldn't be so indifferent
to his whereabouts.
His Majesty could let Zhaoyu return home,
yet why does he show no affection
toward his only legitimate son?
His Majesty isn't necessarily
showing affection to Qin Zhaoyu,
but rather bestowing favour on
those officials
who once served Prince Yan Che
to win their loyalty
and stabilise the court.
If he truly wanted stability,
he wouldn't make a bastard like Yan Qi
the crown prince.
His Majesty might not actually think this,
after all, there's still Sui.
But His Majesty is cold towards Sui
as well.
This is truly strange.
His Majesty is distant and cold
toward his own sons,
yet only in front of Yan Li,
does he act like a loving father.
According to Grandmother,
this change happened
after Consort Jin's tragedy.
Before that,
His Majesty was quite fond
of Sui as well.
Could Consort Jin's death
have changed his temperament
so drastically?
I rarely returned to the capital before.
If you have such questions,
you could ask Grandmother about them.
However,
it is true that
after Prince Jin's incident,
His Majesty became increasingly suspicious
of Father.
It seems Consort Jin's death
is more complicated than we thought.
After we capture Yan Qi,
I'll investigate this matter with you.
For now, we don't know
how far this conspiracy extends.
While you're in the palace,
be extremely careful.
Alright.
Grandmother's pulse is stable and healthy,
she's just not sleeping well,
which is why she feels somewhat fatigued.
Since I entered the palace as a consort
in my teens,
and the palace intrigues
have never ceased.
It's just a fire,
it won't frighten me.
Grandmother.
If you could follow your heart
and make the choice again,
would you still be willing
to enter the palace as a consort?
Everyone living in this world
has their own troubles.
In my entire life,
there were only two times
when I followed my own heart,
and to this day
I still don't know
if they were right or wrong.
But since they were my own decisions,
I have no regrets.
Even when we make our own decisions,
the outcome may not be
what we truly wanted.
That, as well, is the irony of fate.
Take Zhaoyu for example,
if not for His Majesty's mercy,
she would likely be spending
the rest of her life alone
in the forbidden quarters.
Wan.
Let me tell you something.
Don't get too involved in palace affairs.
You and Chi
should live your own life
behind closed doors.
Your Father has
only Chi as his flesh and blood.
Stay as far away from trouble as possible.
I will keep that in mind.
Sui is playing outside.
Go find him.
He's been looking forward to your visit
every day.
Yes.
Any news of Che?
Will His Majesty...
A young eunuch saw Prince Yan Che
leaving the palace,
accompanied by
what appeared to be Lord Zhao's men.
His Majesty promised you
he wouldn't harm Prince Yan Che,
so please don't worry yourself.
Since the fire last night,
he hasn't come to see me once.
He resents me
for pleading on Che's behalf, doesn't he?
If I had known he would be
so cold-hearted,
I...
Empress Dowager,
His Majesty has reached the age of wisdom.
Managing such a vast court,
how could he still be like before,
coming to pay respects to you every day?
-If my Huai...
-Your Majesty.
Alright.
Let's not speak of it.
Let's not.
[Marquis of Zhongyong's Mansion]
Father.
His Majesty has actually allowed Yu
to return home to recover.
What could be his intention?
Silence!
Yan, is Yu coming home?
Go and tidy up
Yu's quarters.
Your Grace, when Yu returns,
will she still be the Crown Princess?
The deposed Crown Prince has already fled,
how can there still be a Crown Princess.
My poor daughter!
Quickly,
bring Madam back to her room.
Yes.
Madam, let's go.
You're not so young anymore,
why do you still
lose your composure so easily?
I was just worried and confused.
But Father,
the honour of
the Marquis of Zhongyong's Mansion
depends entirely on the Eastern Palace.
Nonsense!
The lives of everyone in our household
are in His Majesty's hands.
His Majesty allowing Yu to return
is a warning to us
not to get involved in this matter.
If we harbour any disloyalty again,
His Majesty will execute
our entire family.
Father, are you really willing
to just sit and wait for death?
Everyone in court knows
you're the leader
of Crown Prince's faction,
and that His Majesty
will never trust you again.
Father,
are you just going to watch
as our titles
and everything we've worked for slip away?
While there's still time,
let's immediately send a message
to the Northern Army
and help His Highness rebel.
What a traitor!
The Qin family's titles
were all earned through
loyalty and bravery.
Without loyalty,
how could we still stand
in the imperial court?
No matter how valuable the titles are,
they're not worth
the lives of everyone in our household.
Sui.
Wan.
What's wrong?
Are you unhappy?
I miss Mother.
Come.
Sui,
my mom and dad
have also passed away.
When I miss them,
I talk to the stars in the sky,
and it makes me feel much better.
Do you believe they've gone to heaven?
I do believe so.
I don't know
if there are immortals in heaven,
and my mom used to
scold me and my dad
quite fiercely,
but I know
they were the people who loved me most
in this world.
No matter where they are now,
they would want me to be just like before,
safe and happy.
But I don't have a dad.
I only have Father.
What's that?
Bring us some snacks.
Yes.
Wan, do you trust me?
I trust you.
Then, let me tell you.
I was pretending
to not be able to speak
nor write.
What happened?
Why did you have to pretend?
Because I saw
Father killing Mother.
It was Father,
not Prince Jin.
I saw it with my own eyes.
You were afraid
His Majesty would find out,
so you pretended to be simple-minded?
Father used to treat me as well as
he treats Li.
But since that day,
when Father looks at me,
his eyes are always dark and cold.
Father's temper has gotten worse,
if he finds out, he will surely kill me.
Wan, please believe me.
I believe you.
Don't worry, Sui,
Chi and I will protect you.
Grandmother says you're the best coroner
in Zhou,
I've told you everything,
can you and Chi help me?
I don't want Mother and Prince Jin
to have died in vain.
I promise you.
That day,
I was supposed to join my brothers
at the book appreciation banquet
in the rear garden.
Prince Jin promised me
that he would give me a gift,
but I don't like those adult banquets,
so I pretended to be sick and didn't go.
Instead, I sneaked into Hanguang Hall
to look through Mother's collections.
To my surprise,
Father and Mother returned early,
so I quickly hid behind the curtains.
I ask you,
where did you get this book?
What are you plotting?
Your Majesty might as well tell me,
[Consort Jin]
why is Your Majesty's handwriting
completely different from
that in the book?
Haven't I told you before?
I was once injured.
I hurt my waist, back, and arms,
so naturally my handwriting changed.
I had never seen Father so angry.
I was so scared, I covered my ears.
Sui.
Prince Jin is here.
[Prince Jin]
Quickly, call the imperial physician.
You know nothing,
don't tell anyone,
don't say anything.
Your Highness.
It's all my fault.
If I had dared to rush out then,
Mother wouldn't have died.
If I hadn't forgotten my promise
with Prince Jin,
he wouldn't have suffered this injustice.
Don't think like that.
Sui,
remember this,
your mother's death
has nothing to do with you,
and Prince Jin's suffering
isn't because of you either.
I promise you,
Chi and I
will definitely find out
why His Majesty killed your mother.
Thank you, Wan.
Good child.
Steward Duoshou,
[Xuanji Pavilion]
airing out chess manuals again?
Welcome Prince Rui
Princess Consort Rui,
and Prince Yan Sui.
As Prince Rui said,
I can only do
these minor tasks now.
May I ask what calligraphy samples
Prince Rui is looking for?
I'll just...
No need,
give me the key,
I'll go myself.
Then I'll trouble Prince Rui.
With those old bones of yours,
you should rest well.
Thank you for your concern, Prince Rui.
These chess manuals are just
some beginner's guides,
why does you need to
manage them personally?
Princess Consort Rui may not know,
these few chess manuals,
though not works of masters,
are His Majesty's treasured possessions.
Why would His Majesty
like these books meant for children?
His Majesty is a genius at chess,
often saying that the essence of chess
lies in the simplest principles,
and that all variations
come from the same origin.
These beginner's books
have helped His Majesty
become nearly unbeatable.
Could it be that His Majesty
deliberately loses to the Empress Dowager
and Grand Princess?
It must be due to
His Majesty's filial piety.
Unfortunately, His Majesty
is now busy with state affairs,
and has no time to study chess manuals,
nor express himself
through calligraphy anymore.
Since I have been assigned here,
the Xuanji Pavilion
has not been collecting
any of His Majesty's calligraphy works.
Thank you, Steward.
Please.
Chi.
What is it?
Help me get the one at the top.
The scroll up there.
Which one?
The one in the corner.
This one?
It seems His Majesty
indeed hasn't visited for a long time.
Otherwise, the servants wouldn't dare
to be so negligent.
This was the scroll I saw Mother hiding
the last time I accompanied her
to the Xuanji Pavilion.
Sui,
do you know who wrote this?
Mother said
this is Father's calligraphy
from before he ascended the throne,
which she had found with great difficulty.
These two handwritings
are indeed identical.
The seal on this,
although is His Majesty's personal seal,
differs greatly from the handwriting
in His Majesty's vermilion rescript.
The handwriting on His Majesty's rescripts
is vigorous and sharp,
powerful and forceful,
with none of this harmonious quality.
Chi,
this is what I found
in Mother's calligraphy notes
on the day she died.
Seems like
it was also written
before Father ascended the throne.
The handwriting is identical.
Sui,
does His Majesty know you have this note?
No, he doesn't.
I've never told anyone.
Sui,
go play over there for a while,
I need to speak with Chi.
Those pages and scrolls
that led to Consort Jin's death
must have been disposed by His Majesty.
I still need to carefully compare
His Majesty's calligraphy
from before his ascension,
to better deduce
the true reason why His Majesty
killed Consort Jin.
If what Sui said is true,
then we can confirm
that Prince Jin was framed
for trying to cover up
His Majesty's murder of Consort Jin.
Throughout history,
whenever rulers disregard the law
and kill indiscriminately,
it inevitably leads to public unrest
and gives the disloyal
a justification to fight for the throne.
Therefore,
throughout the ages,
such actions have been seen
as omens of a dynasty's downfall.
But His Majesty prides himself on
being an enlightened ruler
and has always encouraged open criticism.
If news of him killing Consort Jin
were to spread,
it would likely cause court officials
to impeach His Majesty
for breaking laws and moral codes,
leading to turmoil throughout the court.
Therefore,
His Majesty would certainly
try to conceal it by all means.
Prince Jin only knew
that His Majesty killed Consort Jin,
not the reasons behind it.
My father and he never revealed a word
about it,
surely fearing it would cause chaos
in the palace
and even disaster in the court.
Whoever moved Song Xiwen's carcass
to Prince Jin's residence
must know the truth
and intends to make it public.
I fear it's all for the throne.
Then, the Empress must know the truth.
To secure the throne,
she silenced Song Xiwen
to eliminate future troubles
for His Majesty.
No wonder Yan Che
was titled Crown Prince by His Majesty
after this incident.
The Empress and His Majesty
had already reached a concensus.
Everything the Empress did
was likely to ensure Yan Che
could smoothly inherit the throne.
But she did not expect
that His Majesty hates being manipulated
the most.
Eventually, His Majesty
found an opportunity
to remove both her and her son's titles.
How pitiful and tragic.
After Yan Che escaped,
what if he tries to make a comeback?
If our suspicions are correct,
then Yan Che
was deliberately allowed to escape
by His Majesty.
I just hope he doesn't fall into
Prince Cheng's hands,
or his life will be in danger.
What about Sui?
Don't worry, Chi,
I didn't hear anything.
Just like before,
don't say a single word.
Keep playing dumb.
Ambush! Protect His Highness!
I am Yan Che, Crown Prince of Zhou.
How dare you!
Crown Prince of Zhou?
Do you deserve that title?
Yan Qi,
what are you trying to do?
Brother,
this is Mount Beimang,
where all members of our Yan royal family
come to their final rest.
Prince Rui met his end here,
and you
will too.
Uncle died by your hand?
And now, you want to
kill your elder brother?
This place has beautiful mountains
and waters.
This precious spot
is indeed perfect for you.
Am I not being kind enough
as your younger brother?
Shameless!
You think killing Uncle and I
will secure you the Crown Prince position?
Delusional!
Yan Qi!
So talkative.
You've betrayed all morality,
how could Father possibly...
The deposed Crown Prince Yan Che
fled the palace
and secretly contacted the Northern Army
to plot rebellion.
Upon being captured,
knowing he couldn't face the Emperor,
he
took his own life
by slitting his own throat.
All hail Prince Cheng!
So what
if you're the legitimate son?
All hail Prince Cheng!
Empress Dowager!
His Highness
has passed away.
My son!
I am to blame for Che's death.
I shouldn't have been so harsh on him,
nor should I have let him flee the palace.
I only wanted him to live freely.
Now I have to bury my own child.
Your Majesty, please restrain your grief.
Take care of your health.
Che
would be troubled in the afterlife.
My son...
My dear son!
Father.
Father, please don't blame yourself
too much.
It was all my negligence.
I failed to stop Che
from taking such a desperate path.
I am willing to bear all responsibility,
I only ask that
you take care of yourself, Father.
How is this your concern?
If Che
had already decided to end his life,
what could you have done?
Rise.
My son...
Thank you, Father.
My child...
Then I shall take my leave first
and not disturb your rest.
My son...
Prince Rui, please wait.
I have something to report.
That hairpin is truly beautiful.
I've found it.
It was always meant as a gift for you.
Chi.
Tell me the truth.
Do you believe
that Che...
Took his own life?
If Your Majesty doesn't believe it,
then neither do I.
Of course I don't believe it.
Che was gentle by nature.
If he wasn't forced by someone,
how could he take his own life?
I
command you
and Wan
quickly investigate
the cause of Che's death.
You must uncover the whole truth for me
and clear
my son's name.
I obey Your Majesty's command.
My son...
Madam.
We should return to our quarters.
Her Highness never allowed us
into the garden.
Act smart.
A neglected Princess Consort like her
has no right to control me.
You little tramp, what did you say?
Guards!
Throw this tramp into the water!
Do you dare to?
-Let go of me!
-Why wouldn’t I dare?
Remember this.
No matter how neglected I am,
I am still Princess Consort Cheng's wife
appointed by His Majesty.
You...
You're nothing but a lowly woman
who serves with her body.
Do it!
Let me go!
She is indeed a tramp.
But in my eyes,
you're even worse than her.
Prince.
You actually hit me because of her.
Feng Chenbi,
I can spare your life,
but I'm divorcing you.
Go back and tell your father
that from today on,
your family should abandon
any thoughts of manipulating me.
Understand?
Prince.
There's nothing to see here,
let's go.
Your Highness.
Your Highness Prince Cheng,
I, the Duke of Zhong,
am the foremost noble in the capital.
Your maternal family and mine
have been close for generations.
We rise and fall together.
Why cause such embarrassment?
Who's rising and falling with you?
The Duke's mansion today
could enjoy wealth and glory
all because of what my mother and I
have earned for you in the palace.
I am now His Majesty's
only son of age.
Being appointed as Crown Prince
is only a matter of time.
But this Ms. Feng
has none of the dignity
of a future empress.
Duke,
if you still want future prosperity,
then quietly accept this divorce decree
and send your daughter to a nunnery.
If you insist on making trouble,
it wouldn't be difficult for my household
to have a woman die of illness.
Yan Qi, you bastard!
Father.
Go to the palace and ask the Noble Consort
to help us!
Silence!
Haven't we been humiliated enough?
Daughter,
the Noble Consort does care for you,
but she is Prince Cheng's mother first.
Who do you think she'll side with?
So Mother will just let me be divorced
by Prince Cheng?
It's your own fault for not being fertile.
If you had gotten pregnant earlier,
that little tramp wouldn't have
gained the advantage,
causing such embarrassment.
Getting pregnant isn't something
I can just make happen.
The Noble Consort may be favoured
in the palace,
but she only has Yan Qi, doesn't she?
You know nothing about palace affairs.
All these years,
His Majesty has been
giving the Noble Consort beauty pills,
supposedly to preserve her youth.
The Noble Consort has indeed
maintained her beauty,
but consuming too many medicinal compounds
has made it impossible for her
to bear more children.
Why would His Majesty prevent Her Highness
from having more children?
You only need to remember
that royal favour has always been
as thin as paper.
Preserving your own wealth and status
is what matters most.
[Morgue]
Prince Yan Che's limbs were bound,
yet no blood stains were formed.
It suggests that he was bound after death.
There are multiple bruises
on his chest and limbs.
The wound on his neck
is the only fatal injury.
When someone commits suicide
by slitting their throat,
they would experience pain, fear,
and even suffocation
when cutting the throat.
So, their hand strength would weaken
and the wound
would gradually become shallower.
But Prince Yan Che's wound is uniform
in depth.
It's clear the murderer acted swiftly
without any hesitation,
taking away his life with a single stroke.
Prince Yan Che would rather live in prison
than choose such a brutal death,
especially with such a small knife.
What do you plan to do?
Go with the flow.
Follow His Majesty's will.
I have an urgent matter to report.
Minister Li, please speak.
Prince Yan Che's death is a matter
of state importance
and cannot be settled with such haste
based solely on Prince Cheng's testimony.
I humbly request Your Majesty
to have this case
thoroughly investigated
by the Court of Judicial Review.
Li Muyun, what do you mean by this?
There were dozens of soldiers present
at the scene,
what do you mean by "my testimony"?
Your Majesty,
I am Zheng Baishi,
Prefect of the capital prefecture,
and I support Minister Li's proposal.
Zheng Baishi,
are you conspiring with Li Muyun
to falsely accuse me?
Your Highness, you have mistaken.
I merely agreed with Minister Li's
ruling according to the law.
how is that conspiracy?
Prince Rui requests to have an audience.
I have important evidence to present.
Your Majesty.
According to Princess Yongci's
examination,
Prince Yan Che
did not commit suicide,
but had his throat cut by someone else,
killed with a single stroke.
Nonsense!
Che had clearly
took his own life with a dagger.
Based on the wound analysis,
the murder weapon
was a long sword,
not the dagger presented by Prince Cheng.
I have secretly compared
the shape of the Prince Yan Che's wound
with the blade of Prince Cheng's sword,
and they match perfectly.
Absurd!
Utter nonsense!
Father,
he's falsely accusing me!
I...
I ordered you to find Prince Yan Che.
Why did you
bind your brother's limbs
and slit
his throat?
Father...
Because...
Because he...
Because he refused to return with me,
so I ordered him to be bound.
Driven by his anger,
he collided with my sword.
Lies!
Your Majesty!
Prince Yan Che
have died unjustly!
Your Majesty!
Prince Cheng
has long harbored ambitions
to replace the Crown Prince.
He relies on being Your Majesty's
only adult son
and already considers the throne
his for the taking.
He even declared arrogantly
that Ms. Feng is unworthy to be empress,
insisting on divorcing his wife
from my Duke of Zhongguo Residence.
The evidence of Prince Cheng's fratricide
is conclusive.
Your Majesty must not be lenient anymore!
Your Majesty!
Prince...
Prince Cheng, Yan Qi.
You are truly
cruel by nature.
For plotting to seize the crown,
you murdered your own brother.
Court of Judicial Review,
detain and interrogate him!
Your Majesty is wise.
I'd like to see who dares.
Who dares.
All of you.
Every single one of you.
No.
So it was you, Father.
You've been deceiving me all along.
You were the one
who ordered me to kill Prince Yan Che.
Now you blame me for fratricide?
Blame me for fratricide?
Why did you lie to me?
-Why did you lie to me?
-Protect His Majesty!
Treason!
From this day forward,
Yan Qi is stripped of his royal status.
He shall be confined to
the Imperial Clan Court for life.
Go!
Father, why did you deceive me?
I am your only adult son!
Treason!
Father!
Your Majesty!
Please calm your anger, Your Majesty.
Che...
My dear Che...
Chi.
How is His Majesty's condition?
The imperial physician says
His Majesty has suffered too many shocks,
he's overwhelmed
and needs more rest.
Chi.
Why don't we ask His Majesty
to let us leave the capital?
I'm truly tired of this court.
People get executed at the drop of a hat.
It's too stressful.
You can leave if you want.
I still have unfinished business.
What business?
Why don't I know about it?
I'll tell you after I've handled it.
That won't do.
You don't have to tell me your business.
But if you don't leave, neither will I.
As Prince Yi, I may lack in other areas,
but I value loyalty.
I truly live up to my title.
Our brotherhood
far exceeds blood relations.
Let us in this life
share our fortunes together,
steadfast until the end.
Yan Qi.
You've committed many evil deeds.
Must His Majesty spell everything out?
Having me escort you
is already merciful to you.
Just make it easier on yourself.
What are you watching for? Seize him!
Greetings, Prince Rui.
I would appreciate
if Steward Yuan could be accommodating.
I have a few words
to speak privately with commoner Yan Qi.